# **Andrejs Fedjajevs**

### **Data Science & Engineering Consultant**

andrejs.fedjajevs@outlook.com

in linkedin.com/in/fedjajevs/

+31 617 302 901

A data scientist and engineer with 6+ years experience of employing right tools (signal processing, machine learning, AI) to answer business questions or facilitate data-driven decisions. Competent in consultancy research and advanced development projects, in direct contact with stakeholders. Strong individual contributor, with experience as a project and competence team lead.

Looking for opportunities as a data professional with senior responsibilities and a steep learning curve in a tech company striving for efficiency. My goal is to work on data strategy and execution leading to a relevant insight, proof of concept or technology.

## **SKILLS**

#### **Tools**

Python, MATLAB, SQL PyTorch, Keras, xGB PyQt, Plotly, PowerBI, **Azure Cloud** Git Actions, Docker Jira

#### **Expertise**

Signal Processing Machine Learning Deep Learning Dashboards Data Engineering

#### Languages

English Dutch Latvian Russian

#### Coursework & professional interests

Data system design **MLOps** Data governance Edge ML

Design for Six Sigma \*

#### **EXPERIENCE**



**Data Scientist** 

Apr 2022 - Present

Measurement innovations for in-hospital and remote patient monitoring.

- Full-cycle development of AI models for clinical telemonitoring device (activity tracking, gait analysis) in collaboration with business and marketing
- · Oxygenation signal accuracy research and skin color bias problem; Co-authored a publication validating an alternative (non-finger) SpO2 sensor
- · Advocated for better knowledge management practices, promoted KPIs for reusable algorithms and efficient usage of available infrastructure

Imec [1]]ec Senior R&D Engineer

**R&D Enaineer** 

Jan 2021 - Apr 2022 Oct 2016 - Jan 2021

Developed and deployed algorithms&models for vital signs, sleep, stress, activity monitoring, cardiac events, bone healing, neural stimulation from different sensors and modalities (ExG, radar, BioZ, camera, etc.)

- Accountable for end-to-end data storage and processing framework for wearable blood pressure device. Versatile R&D team work led to meeting AAMI standard requirements using in-house designed wristband device
- Build a real-time features extraction pipeline from a portable EEG headset for neuromarketing application. Created a validation framework based on Azure MLOps services and optimized the algorithm for noise and blink removal
- Implemented a real-time deep learning architecture for human gait analysis. Working alongside with partners on use-case formulation, we delivered a solution to track patients' recovery with less burden for patients and practitioners

PM, team leadership, publications and data infrastructure development

- Inno4Health (ITEA consortium project) data analysis&AI task: curated activities for implementing personalized health analytics solutions, stakeholders' management.
- Lead an internal competence team of biomedical algorithm developers: created efficient learning environment and resource management. We improved data analysis work reuse and reliability within the department, promoted more agile approach within non-software-development projects.

#### **EDUCATION**

Master's in Electrical Engineering TUDelft 2014 - 2016

Track: Signals and Systems

Thesis: Ultrasound Imaging Using a Single Element Transducer

Specialist in Electrical Engineering + 5UAL 2009 - 2014

Track: Devices and Methods of Quality Control and Diagnostics